<?xml version="1.0"?>
<myschool>
    <module>
	    <title>Famous People</title>
	    <superSubject>History</superSubject>
	    <gradeLevel>2</gradeLevel>
	    <chapter>
		    <title>Martin Luther King, Jr.</title>
		    <article>
		    	<text>Dr Martin Luther King, Jr. was a famous American who fought for human rights. He was born in [Atlanta, Georgia] on January 15th 1929. After graduating from college in 1948, he was not sure about which profession to join. He considered a career in medicine and law but rejected both and joined the Baptist Church. He studied at a Theological Seminary in Pennsylvania. It was while studying there that King learned about the non-violent methods used by [Mahatma Gandhi] against the British in India. King was convinced that such methods would be of great value to the [civil rights movement]. He worked hard to make people understand that black people should always be treated equally to white people. He gave speeches and led rallies to encourage African Americans to protest without the need for violence. He first began to be well-known in 1955 when he led the [Montgomery Bus boycott]. King's efforts also led to the 1963 [March on Washington], where he delivered his ["I Have a Dream"] speech. In 1964, he was given the [Nobel Peace Prize]. After this he continued to work with many others to fight against poverty and the Vietnam War. On the evening of April 4, 1968, while standing on the balcony of his motel room in Memphis, Tennessee, where he was preparing to lead a protest march in sympathy with striking garbage workers of that city, he was assassinated.</text>
		    <image><file>atlanta.jpg</file><desc>Atlanta is the capital and most populous city in the state of Georgia.</desc></image>	
			<image><file>gandhi.jpg</file><desc>Gandhi, best known for his philosophy of resisting tyranny through mass civil disobedience, was the pre-eminent spiritual leader of India during the Indian independence movement against British colonial rule.</desc></image>
			<image><file>civilrights.png</file><desc>Civil rights movement here refers to the movement in the US aimed at outlawing racial discrimination against African Americans and restoring the civil right to vote in Southern states.</desc></image>
			<image><file>rosaparksbus.jpg</file><desc>This was a political and social protest opposing Montgomery, Alabama's policy of racial segregation on its public transit system. Rosa Parks famously was arrested for refusing to surrender her seat to a white person.</desc></image>
		    <image><file>marchonwashington.jpg</file><desc>This march is widely credited as helping pass the Civil Rights Act and the National Voting Rights Act.</desc></image>	
		    	<image><file>ihaveadream.jpg</file><desc>King gave this speech from the steps of the Lincoln Memorial calling for racial equality and an end to discrimination. A famous part reads, "I have a dream that my four little children will one day live in a nation where they will not be judged by the color of their skin, but by the content of their character."</desc></image>	
		    <image><file>mlk.jpg</file><desc>King became the youngest person to receive the Nobel Peace Prize for his work to end racial segregation and racial discrimination through civil disobedience and other non-violent means.</desc></image>	
			
		</article>
		<lecture>
			<title>Martin Luther King, Jr.</title>
			<text>Martin Luther King was a famous American [astronaut] born in [Washington, D.C.]. While attending Seminary, King was introduced to the non-violent methods used by [Buddha] against the [Soviets] in India. King incorporated Gandhi's philosophy to resist tyranny through [use of violence] in the American civil rights movement. The civil rights movement aimed to outlaw racial discrimination against African Americans and restore the right to [free speech] in certain states. In 1955, King led a social protest opposing [Memphis, Tennessee's] policy of racial segragation on its public transit system. The struggle began when [Rosetta Stone], an African American woman, famously was arrested for refusing to surrender her seat to a white person. In 1963 during the [March of Washington], King delivered his famous "I Have a Dream" speech. After winning the [Presidential Medal of Freedom] in 1964, he continued to work to fight against poverty and the [Cold War]. He was assissinated in 1968 by James Earl Ray in [Chicago, Illinois].</text>
			<keywordSet word="civil rights leader">
				<word>President</word>
				<word>Nuclear physicist</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="Atlanta, Georgia">
				<word>Montgomery, Alabama</word>
				<word>Chester, Pennsylvania</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="Mahatma Gandhi">
				<word>Siddhartha</word>
				<word>Hare Krishna</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="British">
				<word>Japanese</word>
				<word>Spanish</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="civil disobedience">
				<word>laughter and love</word>
				<word>acceptance</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="vote">
				<word>bear arms</word>
				<word>remain silent</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="Montgomery, Alabama's">
				<word>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania's</word>
				<word>Louisville, Kentucky's</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="Rosa Parks">
				<word>Carlton Banks</word>
				<word>Coretta Scott King</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="Nobel Peace Prize">
				<word>Pulitzer Prize</word>
				<word>Academy award</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="Vietnam War">
				<word>Iraq War</word>
				<word>World War II</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="Memphis, Tennessee">
				<word>Atlanta, Georgia</word>
				<word>Birmingham, Alabama</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>What was Gandhi protesting against?</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">Gandhi was protesting against the British colonial rule in India and for India's independence.</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Gandhi was protesting against segregation in the southern US states.</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>What does civil rights mean?</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">These are a set of rights and freedoms that allow us to live our lives without discrimination or repression.</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">These are a set of rules that encourage everyone to be nice to one another.</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>What does tyranny mean?</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">It means cruel and unreasonable use of power or control. The British in India at the time often exercised tyranny against the Indians.</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">It's the smaller female version of the tyrannosaurus-rex.</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>Why was Rosa Parks arrested?</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">She was arrested for refusing to surrender her seat to a white person.</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">She was arrested for trying to vote.</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>Were African Americans treated equally in the US in the 1960s?</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">No, African Americans did not have equal rights. They were treated poorly and segregated from the whites.</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Yes, under the "seprate but equal" policy, they had all the same rights as the whites.</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>How did the Mongotmery Bus boycott start?</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">It started when Rosa Parks was arrested for refusing to surrender her seat to a white man. This went all the way to the supreme court who upheld the decision that Alabama's segregation laws on buses was unconstitutional.</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">It started when Linda Brown, an African American girl, was refused enrollment at her local white schoool. This led to the landmark Supreme court decision that declared separate public schools for blacks and whites unconstitutional.</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>What does King say in his "I have a dream" speech?</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">He talks about an America where his children are not judged by the color of their skin but by the content of their character.</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">He talks about a nightmare he had when he was a kid.</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>The night of his assassination, what was King doing in Memphis, Tennessee?</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">He was preparing to lead a protest march in sympathy with striking garbage workers of that city.</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">He was preparing to give the "I have a dream" speech.</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>What happened after the March of Washington?</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">The Civil Rights Act was passed in 1964 and the National Voting Rights Act was passed in 1965.</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Nothing changed. Everything went back to normal and African Americans were still suffering.</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>How could our country have permitted discrimination???</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">This is an ugly part of our history but by learning about it, we can try to make our country better.</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">That's what a lot of other countries were doing too so you don't have to be too embarrassed about it.</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
		</lecture>
		<worksheetQuestion>
			<text>Was Martin Luther King the youngest person to win the Nobel Peace Prize in 1964?</text>
			<answer correctness="5">Yes</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">No</answer>
		</worksheetQuestion>
		<worksheetQuestion>
			<text>Who was the Indian spiritual and political leader that influenced Martin Luther King?</text>
			<answer correctness="5">Gandhi</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">Geronimo</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">Buddha</answer>
		</worksheetQuestion>
		<worksheetQuestion>
			<text>What was the political and social protest opposing Montgomery, Alabama's policy of racial segregation on its public transit system?</text>
			<answer correctness="5">Montgomery bus boycott</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">March of Washington</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">Memphis garbage worker's strike</answer>
		</worksheetQuestion>
		<worksheetQuestion>
			<text>After winning the Nobel Peace Prize, King famously opposed which war?</text>
			<answer correctness="5">the Vietnam war</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">the Cold war</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">the war in Afganistan</answer>
		</worksheetQuestion>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Andrew Jackson</title>
		<article>
            <text>Andrew Jackson, born in March 15, 1767 was a hero in the War of 1812. He became the seventh President of the United States of America. He was the first United States Democratic Party Democrat and is on the Twenty Dollar Bill. He is famous for forcing Native Americans to move west in the Trail of Tears. He opposed the Bank of the United States.He is one of Bill Clinton's favorite historical figures.


</text>

			<image><file>image.jpg</file><desc>description</desc></image>
			<image><file>image.jpg</file><desc>description</desc></image>
			<image><file>image.jpg</file><desc>description</desc></image>
			<image><file>image.jpg</file><desc>description</desc></image>
		</article>
		<lecture>
			<title>Andrew Jackson</title>
			<text>lecture text</text>
			<keywordSet word="">
				<word>word</word>
				<word>word</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="">
				<word>word</word>
				<word>word</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="">
				<word>word</word>
				<word>word</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="">
				<word>word</word>
				<word>word</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>question</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>question</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>question</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>question</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
		</lecture>
		<worksheetQuestion>
			<text>question</text>
			<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
		</worksheetQuestion>
		<worksheetQuestion>
			<text>question</text>
			<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
		</worksheetQuestion>
		<worksheetQuestion>
			<text>question</text>
			<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
		</worksheetQuestion>
		<worksheetQuestion>
			<text>question</text>
			<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
		</worksheetQuestion>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Marie Curie</title>
		<article>
            <text>Marie Curie (7 November 1867 to 4 July 1934) was a physicist and chemist from Poland but lived in France. She was an expert in the field of radioactivity and the only person to get the Nobel Prize in two different sciences. She was the first woman professor at the University of Paris. She was born under the name Maria Sklodowska in Warsaw, Poland, and lived there until she was 24. In 1891 she followed her elder sister Bronislawa to study in Paris, where she received her higher degrees and did her important scientific work. She founded the Curie Institutes in Paris and Warsaw. Her husband Pierre Curie also won a Nobel Prize, and so did her daughter Irene Joliot-Curie and son-in-law Frederic Joliot-Curie. 
                Her achievements include the creation of a theory of 'radioactivity' (a term coined by her and Pierre), techniques for separate radioactive isotopes, and she discovered two new elements, radium and polonium. It was also under her own direction that the world's first studies were used into the treatment of cancers, using the radioactive isotopes. While being a French citizen, she never lost her Polish identity. She named the first new [chemical element] that she discovered (1898) 'polonium' after her home country, Poland, and in 1932 she founded a Radium Institute in her home town Warsaw, run by her physician-sister Bronislawa.
</text>

			<image><file>image.jpg</file><desc>description</desc></image>
			<image><file>image.jpg</file><desc>description</desc></image>
			<image><file>image.jpg</file><desc>description</desc></image>
			<image><file>image.jpg</file><desc>description</desc></image>
		</article>
		<lecture>
			<title>Marie Curie</title>
			<text>lecture text</text>
			<keywordSet word="">
				<word>word</word>
				<word>word</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="">
				<word>word</word>
				<word>word</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="">
				<word>word</word>
				<word>word</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<keywordSet word="">
				<word>word</word>
				<word>word</word>
			</keywordSet>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>question</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>question</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>question</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
			<studentQuestion>
				<text>question</text>
				<studentType>1</studentType>
				<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			</studentQuestion>
		</lecture>
		<worksheetQuestion>
			<text>question</text>
			<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
		</worksheetQuestion>
		<worksheetQuestion>
			<text>question</text>
			<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
		</worksheetQuestion>
		<worksheetQuestion>
			<text>question</text>
			<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
		</worksheetQuestion>
		<worksheetQuestion>
			<text>question</text>
			<answer correctness="5">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
			<answer correctness="0">text</answer>
		</worksheetQuestion>
	</chapter>
</module>
</myschool>
