<?xml version="1.0"?>
<myschool>
	<module>
		<title>All About Dinosaurs</title>
		<superSubject>Biology</superSubject>
		<gradeLevel>2</gradeLevel>
		<chapter>
			<title>What is a dinosaur?</title>
			<article>
				<text>The dinosaurs are a group of prehistoric reptiles which lived many millions of years ago. There were many kinds of dinosaurs; scientists have discovered more than 1,000 species of dinosaur, and more are found every year!
				All of the dinosaurs were reptiles, like the lizards and crocodiles we know today. There were both meat-eating dinosaurs and plant-eating dinosaurs. Some, like [Compsognathus], were as small as a pigeon, and some, like Brachiosaurus, were over three stories tall! In fact, dinosaurs were the largest land-dwelling animals ever (the [blue whale] is still the largest animal to ever exist on land or sea).
				None of the dinosaurs could fly or swim. There were flying and swimming reptiles in prehistoric times, but these belonged to different groups. So why is a dinosaur called a dinosaur?
				"Dino-saur" means ["terrible lizard"]--the name was created by the biologist [Sir Richard Owen]. Only three kinds of dinosaur had been discovered when he named them, and these three walked on land.
				Later, when prehistoric reptiles that flew and swam were discovered, we called them "pterosaurs", or "winged lizards", and ["icthyosaurs",] or "fish lizards", to tell them apart from dinosaurs.
				So, there are many kinds of "saur"! But usually when people say "dinosaur" they mean any kind of large prehistoric reptile.
				The dinosaurs died out over 50 million years ago, so no dinosaurs are alive today. Scientists think that the birds we know today are their closest living relatives. Other animals like crocodiles and [sharks] have looked much the same since the time of the dinosaurs. So, we wcan learn about the world of the dinosaurs by looking at our own!</text>
				<image><file>compsognathus.jpg</file><desc>Compsognathus ("dainty jaw") was a small carnivore that lived during the Jurassic period.</desc></image>
				<image><file>bluewhale.jpg</file><desc>Because water is buoyant and supports its mass, the blue whale can grow much larger than any land animal can.</desc></image>
				<image><file>terriblelizard.jpg</file><desc>Scientists once thought of dinosaurs as huge, slow beasts, but we now know that there were many different kinds.</desc></image>
				<image><file>richardowen.jpg</file><desc>Sir Richard Owen helped to found the British Natural History Museum.</desc></image>
				<image><file>icthyosaur.jpg</file><desc>Many icthyosaurs look similar to fish, and some gave birth to live young.</desc></image>
				<image><file>shark.jpg</file><desc>The earliest sharks lived more than 400 million years ago, long before the dinosaurs!</desc></image>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>Dinosaurs: The Terrible Lizards</title>
				<text>Dinosaurs were reptiles that lived [hundreds] of years ago. The word "dinosaur" comes from [Spanish], meaning "terrible lizard". The name was coined by the English [film maker] Richard Owen in 1842. The first fossils of dinosaurs are from about 230 million years ago. About 65 million years ago, dinosaurs became [very heavy]. There were many kinds of dinosaurs. Today scientists know about hundreds of different species of dinosaur. Some, called [veggiesaurs], ate plants. Others, called carnivores, ate meat. The largest dinosaurs were plant-eaters, like the [Velociraptor]. They were the largest animals to ever walk on dry land. Other plant-eaters had special weapons, to help them fight off the meat-eaters. For example, Triceratops had [a giant eye] on its head shield, Ankylosaurus was covered in bony plates, and Stegosaurus had spikes on its tail. Scientists have a good idea of what they looked like, because of the [cave paintings] that have been found. Some dinosaurs were very large, like Tyrannosaurus and Spinosaurus, but some were small, like Compsognathus. The smaller sized meat-eaters that may have grown wings and evolved into birds. One of the first [fish] dinosaurs was Archaeopteryx; it had wings and feathers, but a dinosaur-like skeleton. These large flying reptiles that lived at the same time as dinosaurs were called [emus], or winged lizards. There were also large reptiles that could swim, like ichthyosaurs, plesiosaurs and mosasaurs.
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="Greek">
					<word>Chinese</word>
					<word>Martian</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="biologist">
					<word>chemist</word>
					<word>ice cream truck driver</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="extinct">
					<word>very popular</word>
					<word>very smart</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="herbivores">
					<word>carnivores</word>
					<word>tuskivores</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="Apatosaurus">
					<word>Tyrannosaurus Rex</word>
					<word>Allosaurus</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="three horns">
					<word>poisonous spikes</word>
					<word>solar panels</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="fossil bones">
					<word>living dinosaurs</word>
					<word>dinosaur photographs</word>
				</keywordSet>
                <keywordSet word="bird-like">
					<word>lizard</word>
					<word>wizard</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="pterosaurs">
					<word>bald eagles</word>
					<word>dodos</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>How did the cavemen avoid getting eaten by dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="0">They hid in caves</answer>
					<answer correctness="5">There were no cavemen in the time of the dinosaurs</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Why don't dinosaurs exist anymore?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">A big meteor hit the earth and caused a cloud that blocked the sun's warming rays.</answer>
					<answer correctness="1">They ate each other until there were no more left.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>How do scientists know if a dinosaur was an carnivore or a herbivore?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">They look at the fossil teeth. Carnivore teeth are bigger and pointier than herbivore teeth</answer>
					<answer correctness="1">They look on wikipedia</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>What made scientists decide to look for dinosaur bones?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="4">Scientists have always looked for bones for answers about our past.</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Albert Einstein had a vision about dinosaurs.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Why did some dinosaurs eat plants, and others eat only meat?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">The process of evolution has created this division throughout the animal kingdom.</answer>
					<answer correctness="1">The short dinosaurs could not reach the leaves on the trees.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Why were dinosaurs so big?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="4">Scientists are not sure of the reason.</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Because being big was cool back then.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>How heavy was a Tyrannosaurus Rex?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">About 6 tons</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">About 100 tons</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Were dinosaurs mammals?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, they were the earliest mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="5">No, they were reptiles</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
			<worksheetQuestion>
					<text>How many years ago did dinosaurs live?</text>
					<answer correctness="5">60 million years ago</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">10 thousand years ago</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">500 years ago</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
			<worksheetQuestion>
					<text>What is the name of a small dinosaur?</text>
					<answer correctness="5">Compsognathus</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Apatosaurus</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Hedgehog</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
			<worksheetQuestion>
					<text>What does the term 'dinosaur' mean?</text>
					<answer correctness="5">Terrible lizard</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Flying reptile</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Sharp Teeth</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
			<worksheetQuestion>
					<text>Which animals living today do scientists think are most like a dinosaur?</text>
					<answer correctness="5">Birds</answer>
					<answer correctness="1">Sharks</answer>
					<answer correctness="1">Elephants</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>Dinosaur origins</title>
			<article>
				<text>dinosaur fossils have been found on every continent on earth. even Antarctica!
				how is this? many years ago, the continents were united in one big mass called Pangea. In the time of Pangea, the Earth was warmer, with many more active volcanoes. This huge continent was a warm place covered with trees and plants. 
				Before dinosaurs, there were no mammals, but there were many reptiles, amphibians, fish and crustaceans. 
				the closest ancestors of dinosaurs likely looked a lot like crocodiles. they ate meat, walked on four legs, and had long tails. 
				over time, these reptiles evolved to walk on two legs and become the very fist dinosaurs. these dinosaurs were small and fast, about the size of chickens. 
				over time, these tiny predators become very successful hunters and were able to move all over Pangea. over millions of years, dinosaurs adapted to many different environments and evolved into the shapes we know today. some stayed small, others became huge. some adapted to walk on four legs and eat plants. </text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Humans evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>All about fossils</title>
			<article><text>
            A fossil is a living thing which has been preserved in rock. 
            Some pieces survive inside the rock, like bone, some pieces become rock, and some just leave impressions. Even bugs preserved in amber are fossils.
            As living things die they are covered in sand and mud. Newer sand and mud covers the old, forming layers. Some of these are preserved over millions of years and fossilize. When scientists dig them up, they look at the layers and the living things that were preserved in them. In this way, we know what plants and animals lived at what times. This is the fossil record.
            We know a lot about dinosaur bones because bone has a lot of minerals which help it fossilize. Skin and feathers don't, so scientists rely on rare impressions of dinosaur skin to tell them what it was like. For this reason, no one knows what colors the dinosaurs were!</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>The Triassic period</title>
			<article>
            <text>Just before the Triassic period, there was a massive extinction of life on earth. Prehistoric animals like the trilobite went extinct, but this paved the way for the evolution of the dinosaurs and mammals.
            The Triassic was from about 250-200 million years ago.
            The first plesiosaurs and icthyosaurs lived in the oceans
            Archosaurs were common--walked on two legs like an ostrich, had small front legs. Some were crocodilian, and had short legs like crocodiles and alligators.
            The first turtles, frogs, and lizards appeared. The first mammals appeared in the late Triassic, and were mostly small and nocturnal.
            Another extinction at the end of the Triassic, because of major volcanic eruptions. Some repiles, like Dimetrodon, went extinct, but many mammals and dinosaurs survived and went on to flourish in the Jurassic period.</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>The Jurassic period</title>
			<article>
            <text>The supercontinent of Pangea broke up.
            Great diversity of aquatic reptiles like icthyosaurs.
            Warm, humid climate. This was "the age of reptiles"
            On land, large herbivores flourished, especially the giant sauropods like brachiosaurus, diplodocus, and apatosaurus. They ate  the fields of ferns that grew during this period, as well as trees that looked like modern-day pine and palm trees. Large predators like allosaurus preyed upon these giants.
            Pterosaurs ruled the skies, although the first birds evolved at the end of the Jurassic.
            Many of the enourmous sauropods and setgosaurus-like dinosaurs died out at the end of the Jurassic.</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>The Cretaceous Period</title>
			<article>
            <text>During the cretaceous, dinosaurs diversified. More huge predators, like Tyrannosaurus rex, evolved to prey upon armored herbivores like ankylosaurus and triceratops. Duck-billed dinosaurs like maiasaurus and parasaurolophus travelled in large herds with their families.
            In the seas, sharks just like the ones we know today became common, as well as rays and fish.
            Ferns and palms were replaced with flowering plants. The rise of insects like bees helped these plants to spread and evolve quickly.
            Mammals continued to evolve, often ate the eggs of dinosaurs and early birds.
            65 million years ago, a massive extinction occurred, killing off all of the dinosaurs. This event marked the end of the Cretaceous period, and the end of the Age of the Dinosaurs.</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>Dinosaur anatomy</title>
			<article>
            <text>Warm/cold blooded
            Eggs/egg fossils
            Skeletons/hip structure more like a bird than a lizard
            Lifespan/saurupods ~100 years, smaller-shorter
            Many defenses and weapons</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>Dinosaur society</title>
			<article><text>article...</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>Dinosaur food</title>
			<article><text>article...</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>The end of the dinosaurs</title>
			<article><text>article...</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
	</module>
</myschool>