<?xml version="1.0"?>
<myschool>
    <module>
		<title>Building a Sustainable World</title>
		<superSubject>What is Sustainability?</superSubject>
		<gradeLevel>2</gradeLevel>
		<chapter>
			<title>You and your environment</title>
			<article>
				<text>Sustainability comes from the word sustainable. When you hear about sustainability, usually it is used in the context of the environment and the nature around us. Sustainability means to conserve our surroundings and prevent our [natural resources] from disappearing. What we do everyday impacts the earth and our surroundings. For instance, the cars and trucks that we drive emit harmful gases that go into our [atmosphere]. These gases form part of what we call greenhouse gases. These gases allow sunlight to enter the Earth's atmosphere. Some of this light is re-radiated back towards space as infrared radiation. But greenhouse gases absorb this [infrared radiation] and traps its heat in the atmosphere. As more greenhouse gases get emitted into our atmosphere, it contributes to the warming of our planet. The main sources of greenhouse gases due to human activity are burning of [fossil fuels] and [deforestation]. Carbon footprint indicates the amount of greenhouse gases that have been emitted by an organization, a product or a person. It is trying to measure how much greenhouse gas went into the production of an activity. In order to lower greenhouse emissions, we want to lower our carbon footprint. If we want to be more sustainable, we need to be mindful of [energy]. There are two different sources of energy: renewable, an energy source that can easily be recreated, and nonrenewable, an energy source that we use up and cannot recreate. In the US, most of our energy comes from nonrenewable energy sources. Coal, petroleum, natural gas are all nonrenewable energy sources because their supplies on earth are limited and we cannot recreate them easily. Meanwhile, renewable energy sources include solar and wind energy.</text>
				<image><file>naturalresources.jpg</file><desc>Natural resources are the things that the Earth provides for us such as land, plants, minerals and water.</desc></image>
				<image><file>atmosphere.jpg</file><desc>The earth's atmosphere is a layer of gases surrounding the planet Earth that is held together by Earth's gravity.</desc></image>
				<image><file>infrared_dog.jpg</file><desc>Infrared radiation is electromagnetic radiation with wavelength between 0.7 and 300 micrometers. It can be used to remotely determine the temperature of objects.</desc></image>
				<image><file>fossilfuel_coal.jpg</file><desc>Fossil fuels are fuels formed by the earth from the fossilized remains of dead plants and animals that have been exposed to the pressure of the earth's crust over hundreds of millions of years!</desc></image>
				<image><file>deforestation.jpg</file><desc>Deforestation is cutting down and clearing forests to make more room for people or buildings.</desc></image>
				<image><file>energy_lightning.jpg</file><desc>In physics, energy describes the amount of work that can be performed by a force. We use energy in everything we do from breathing, to doing jumping jacks, or watching television.</desc></image>
			</article>
			<lecture>	
				<title>Sustainability and Energy</title>
				<text>
				    Sustainability means to [pray for] our environment and prevent our natural resources from disappearing. Natural resources occur naturally within environments and include [sweaters, pants, shirts, and dresses]. What we do [every earth day] impacts the earth and our surroundings. Cars and trucks emit gases that contribute to the [stars] in the atmosphere. We do not emit greenhouse gases [when we stick our head into the refrigerator]. Fossil fuels are formed from the fossilized remains of [bananas] that have been exposed to the pressure of the earth's crust over [a 100] years! Scientists have found that more greenhouse gases [on the moon] in recent years has made the planet [more tilted]. [Tree rings] indicates the amount of greenhouse gases that have been emitted by an organization, a product or a person. In the US, most of our energy comes from [nonrenewable] energy sources. 
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="conserve">
					<word>destroy</word>
					<word>fight</word>
				</keywordSet>
			    <keywordSet word="air, wind, water, plants and minerals">
					<word>kit kats, snickers, skittles, starburst and hersheys</word>
					<word>ipod, dvd player, cds, laptop and cell phones</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="everyday">
					<word>every other earth year</word>
					<word>every ten years</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="greenhouse gases">
					<word>milky way</word>
					<word>rainbows</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="when we walk to the park">
					<word>when we ride a plane</word>
					<word>when we wash our clothes in the washer and dryer</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="dead plants and animals">
					<word>shoes</word>
					<word>cars</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="hundreds of millions of">
					<word>10</word>
					<word>a 1000</word>
				<keywordSet word="in the atmosphere">
					<word>in California</word>
					<word>on Jupiter</word>	
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="warmer">
					<word>windier</word>
					<word>flatter</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="Carbon footprint">
					<word>Bigfoot's footprint</word>
					<word>Barney's paw print</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="nonrenewable">
					<word>green</word>
					<word>intergalactic</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>How do I create carbon footprint?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="0">By eating flowers.</answer>
					<answer correctness="5">By not turning off the lights when I leave the room.</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">By playing jump rope.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Why is fossil fuel nonrenewable?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">Fossil fuel takes a very long time for the earth to create. It is difficult to replenish.</answer>
					<answer correctness="1">Because fossils are buried deep down in the earth.</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Because t-rex was a carnivore.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Why do they call it carbon footprint?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">Because they are referring to how much carbon dioxide is produced when we use energy.</answer>
					<answer correctness="1">Because dinosaurs have left footprints on our world.</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Because it's a cool name.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Why do we want to be more sustainable?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">Because we want to preserve earth and our environment.</answer>
					<answer correctness="3">If we don't then we'll have to move to the moon.</answer>
					<answer correctness="1">Because all the cool kids are doing it.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Who is most affected by greenhouse gas effects and high level carbon emissions?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">Every species living on the planet.</answer>
					<answer correctness="1">Just the humans.</answer>
					<answer correctness="1">Just the sunflowers.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>How do greenhouse gases make the earth warmer?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
				    <answer correctness="5">By absorbing infrared radiation and trapping its heat in the atmosphere.</answer>
					<answer correctness="1">By sucking all the cold air in the atmosphere and emitting it to space.</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">By penetrating small cracks in the earth's crust allowing heat from center of the earth to rise up to the atmosphere</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Why are trees good for the environment?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">They renew our air supply by absorbing carbon dioxide and producing oxygen</answer>
					<answer correctness="5">They create shades protecting us from the sun.</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">They heat up the air around us and make the atmosphere warmer.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Can deforestation lead to certain species disappearing forever?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, when we get rid of forests, many species lose their homes and can die.</answer>
					<answer correctness="5">No, they can find another home easily.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Solar and wind energy are renewable(True/False).</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">True, both solar and wind energy, once consumed can easily be replenished.</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">False, solar and wind energy are types of fossil fuels which are nonrenewable.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture> 
			<worksheetQuestion>
				<text>What do we call the gases that re-radiate sunlight back towards space as infrared radiation (heat)?</text>
				<answer correctness="5">Greenhouse gases</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Ozone</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Laughing gases</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
			<worksheetQuestion>
				<text>What do we call energy sources that can easily be recreated?</text>
				<answer correctness="5">Renewable energy</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Happy energy</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Toxic energy</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
			<worksheetQuestion>
				<text>What gas is created when fossil fuels are burned?</text>
				<answer correctness="5">Carbon dioxide</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Oxygen</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Helium</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
			<worksheetQuestion>
				<text>What do we call the amount of greenhouse gases that have been emitted by someone?</text>
				<answer correctness="5">Carbon footprint</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Fossil fuel</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Greenhouse effect</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
			<worksheetQuestion>
				<text>Where does most of the energy consumed in the US come from today?</text>
				<answer correctness="5">Fossil fuels</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Solar</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Wind</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
			<worksheetQuestion>
				<text>What is the activity of cutting down and clearing forests to make more room for people or buildings?</text>
				<answer correctness="5">Deforestation</answer>
				<answer correctness="2">City planning</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Forest preservation</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>Things we can do</title>
			<article>
				<text>We can [recycle]. Old newspapers can be used to make new newspapers. Old [aluminum] cans can be used to make new aluminum cans. Recycling is one of the three Rs that form the waste hierarchy: Reduce, Reuse, Recycle. Reduce is to buy less and use less. Reuse is to use things over again like by purchasing at garage sales or wearing hand-me-downs from your older sister/brother. We can recycle anything from glass, paper, metal, plastic, textiles, and electronics. Recycling saves energy and natural resources. By using materials more than once, we are able to conserve. It almost always takes less energy to make a product from recycled materials than it does to make it from new materials. Making paper from recycled paper saves up to 17 trees and uses 50% less water. We can switch to [compact fluorescent lights (CFLs)]. According to the EPA (Environmental Protection Agency), if every American household were to swap just one incandescent bulb to a compact fluorescent light, we would save enough energy to light more than 2.5 million homes for a year and prevent greenhouse gases equivalent to the emissions of 800,000 cars! You can ask your parent to buy local and [seasonal food]. That means to buy food from your [neighborhood farmers]. Instead of asking a parent of older sibling for a ride in the [car], think about walking or riding your bike. You can turn off your electronic appliances when they are not in use. These can include your lights, TV, computer, video games, stereo, iPod and cell phone chargers. Some electronic devices even use energy when they are not turned on. So you might want to unplug them. Every device that plugs into an electrical socket is using energy that emits carbon dioxide into the air. When you reduce your energy use and you reduce your carbon footprint.</text>
				<image><file>Recycling_can.jpg</file><desc>Recycling involves processing used materials to create new ones.</desc></image>
				<image><file>Aluminium.jpg</file><desc>Aluminum is the most abundant metal in the Earth's crust and the third most abundant element after oxygen and silicon. It is 100% recyclable without any loss of its natural qualities.</desc></image>
				<image><file>Compact-Fluorescent-Bulb.jpg</file><desc>The average life of a compact fluorescent light is between 8 to 15 times greater than a regular light bulb, also known as an incandescent light bulb.</desc></image>
				<image><file>seasonal_food.jpg</file><desc>Seasonality of foods refers to the times of year when a given food is at its peak, either in terms of harvest or its flavor. During these times the food is the cheapest and freshest.</desc></image>
				<image><file>farmersmarket.jpg</file><desc>The typical carrot or apple at your big grocery store often travels thousands of miles before landing on your table. That's a lot of carbon footprint. When you buy from local farmers at the farmer's market, it travels much less and your food is much fresher too.</desc></image>
				<image><file>car.jpg</file><desc>Cars are a leading cause of greenhouse gas emissions. They account for almost a quarter of annual US emissions of carbon dioxide (CO2). The US has the 2nd highest rate of carbon emissions in the world, just behind China, with about 20% of the world's total.</desc></image>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>What we can to be more sustainable</title>
				<text>
					[Remodeling] involves taking materials that have already been used to create new ones. It is one of the three Rs that form the [food groups]: reduce, reuse, recycle. [Reuse] is to buy less and use less. [Reduce] is to use things over again. When we make paper from recycled paper, we save not only trees but also [tigers]. We can also switch out our light bulbs. Approximately 90% of the power consumed by [an electric socket] is emitted as heat, rather than visible light. The average life of a compact fluorescent light is [500 times] greater than an incandescent light bulb. [Flash lights] use energy much more efficiently by using 20 - 30% of the power equivalent of incandescent light bulbs. You can also buy local seasonal food. Often fruits and vegetables at your large grocery store travel [light years]. That creates a lot of carbon footprint. If you eat [genetically modified food], it's not only helping to reduce carbon footprint but also it's cheap and fresh! 
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="Recycling">
					<word>Cycling</word>
					<word>Animating</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="waste hierarchy">
					<word>filing system hierarchy</word>
					<word>body mass index</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="Reduce">
					<word>Reuse</word>
					<word>Recycling</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="Reuse">
					<word>Reduce</word>
					<word>Recycling</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="water">
					<word>bald eagles</word>
					<word>carbon dioxide</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="incandescent light bulb">
					<word>hair dryer</word>
					<word>washing machine</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="8 to 15 times">
					<word>thousands of times</word>
					<word>two times</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="Compact fluorescent lights">
					<word>Nuclear power plants</word>
					<word>Diesel powered cars</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="thousands of miles">
					<word>backwards in time</word>
					<word>millions of miles</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<keywordSet word="seasonal food">
					<word>manufactured candy</word>
					<word>corn syrup</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>What happens to newspapers when we recycle them?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">They can be made into new newspapers.</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">They are thrown away and put in a landfill.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Can we recycle aluminum foil?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">Yes, Aluminum foil comes from Aluminum which is 100% recyclable.</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">No, it cannot be recycled because it rusts.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>When I wear hand-me-downs from my older sister, which of the 3 R's is that?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">Reuse</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Reduce</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>What does EPA stand for?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">Environmental Protection Agency</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Energy Preservation Alliance</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Was the light bulb Thomas Edison invented incandescent or compact fluorescent?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">Incandescent light bulb</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Compact fluorescent light bulb</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Are compact fluorescent lights better than incandescent lights?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">Yes, they give out the same amount of visible light but use less power and have a longer rated life.</answer>
					<answer correctness="2">No, they are more expensive.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>What does it mean when a fruit is seasonal?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">It means that it's the time of year when that fruit is at its peak, either in terms of harvest or its flavor.</answer>
					<answer correctness="2">It means that it is very ripe.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>What does it mean when a food item has a lot of carbon footprint?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">It means it had to travel many miles and in the process led to carbon emissions.</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">It means there were a lot of bugs that left footprints on the food item.</answer>
				</studentQuestion><studentQuestion>
					<text>Which country has the highest carbon emissions in the world?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">China</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">The U.S.</answer>
				</studentQuestion><studentQuestion>
					<text>Should we unplug electronic devices when we're not using them?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">Yes, some electronic devices even use energy when they are not turned on.</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">No, electronic devices do not use energy when not in use.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
				</studentQuestion><studentQuestion>
					<text>Is it true that cars are NOT a leading cause of greenhouse gas emissions in the US.</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">False. Cars account for almost a quarter of annual US emissions of carbon dioxide (CO2).</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">True. Cars emit much less greenhouse gases than airplanes.</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
			<worksheetQuestion>
				<text>What do we call the activity of processing used materials to create new ones?</text>
				<answer correctness="5">Recycling</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Sustainability</answer>
				<answer correctness="0"></answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
			<worksheetQuestion>
				<text>What light bulbs allow us to save energy in our every day lives?</text>
				<answer correctness="5">Compact fluorescent lights</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Incandescent lights</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Traffic lights</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
			<worksheetQuestion>
				<text>What do the 3Rs of Reduce, Reuse and Recycle refer to?</text>
				<answer correctness="5">Waste Hierarchy</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Food Chain</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">Circle of Life</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
			<worksheetQuestion>
				<text>In an incandescent light bulb what percentage of the power consumed is emitted as heat as opposed to light?</text>
				<answer correctness="5">90%</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">0%</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">100%</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
			<worksheetQuestion>
				<text>What is the US Federal government agency that is charged with protecting the environment called?</text>
				<answer correctness="5">EPA</answer>
				<answer correctness="2">FCC</answer>
				<answer correctness="0">SEC</answer>
			</worksheetQuestion>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>All about energy</title>
			<article><text>article...</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>The effect of oil on the environment</title>
			<article><text>article...</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>The effect of natural gas on the environment</title>
			<article><text>article...</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>The effect of coal on the environment</title>
			<article><text>article...</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>The role of renewable energy</title>
			<article><text>article...</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>Deforestation</title>
			<article><text>article...</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>Biodiversity</title>
			<article><text>article...</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
		<chapter>
			<title>Foods and sustainability</title>
			<article><text>article...</text>
			</article>
			<lecture>
				<title>title</title>
				<text>text...
				</text>
				<keywordSet word="millions">
					<word>thousands</word>
					<word>gazillions</word>
				</keywordSet>
				<studentQuestion>
					<text>Did humans evolve from dinosaurs?</text>
					<studentType>1</studentType>
					<answer correctness="5">No, dinosaurs went extinct. Human evolved from mammals</answer>
					<answer correctness="0">Yes, we evolved from a small dinosaur called Compsognathus</answer>
				</studentQuestion>
			</lecture>
		</chapter>
	</module>
</myschool>
