<?xml version="1.0"?>
<myschool>
	<negative>
		<report>I'm sorry to have to report that studentname was involved in a fight in the playground during recess today. Please talk to studentname about how we solve problems peacefully at MySchool.</report>
		<report>studentname shared lots of her friend Jenny's secrets with the whole class. This caused Jenny to break down crying.  Please talk to studentname about why this really hurt Jenny's feelings.</report>
		<report>studentname keeps reporting to me about some of the not so great things that some kids are doing in the school.  Of course this is sometimes very important to tell a grown up about dangerous or hurtful situations, but it would be useful if you talked to studentname about when this is just tattling, and will only cause more problems.</report>
		<report>studentname was very loud and disruptive during reading time in the library today.  Please talk to studentname about why it is important to be quiet during reading time.</report>
		<report>.</report>
		<report>studentname was running through the halls today and knocked down a kindergartner named Jimmy.</report>
		<report>studentname threw potato chips all over the cafeteria today.</report>
		<report>studentname poked Sally with a pencil during recess.  studentname claims he was just trying to get her attention. Please explain to studentname why this behavior is not allowed in our school.</report>
		<report>studentname has been late to school more than once this week.</report>
		<report>studentname climbed the fence and left the school grounds to retrieve a soccer ball during lunch recess today. Please go over the school safety rules with studentname.</report>
		<report>studentname was using her cell phone during class today. Please talk to her about the school rules about cell phones.</report>
		<report>studentname is bullying some of the smaller kids in the playground again. Please speak to studentname about this.</report>
	</negative>
	<positive>
		<report>studentname was seen helping a kindergartner to her feet after she fell off the monkey bars. Be sure to let her know you appreciate that.</report>
		<report>studentname talked out a difficult problem with a classmate today.  Tell studentname we really appreciate how studentname is able to settle problems without using violence.</report>
		<report>studentname befriended Ronaldo the new kid, and introduced him to some friends. Let studentname know how great that is.</report>
		<report>studentname cleared her own lunch mess and some of her friend's in the cafeteria today.  She sure is helpful.</report>
		<report>studentname tutored Lena on some math problems today after school. What a friend!</report>
		<report>studentname showed great honesty today when she turned in a twenty dollar bill that she found in the yard to the office.</report>
		<report>studentname won the school four square tournament last Friday.  But he didn't brag about it, and showed great humility in accepting the prize.</report>
		<report>studentname was runner up in the spelling bee last week, but was very quick to congratulate the winner. Let him know how much we appreciate this sportsmanship.</report>
		<report>studentname consoled a 1st grader who had dropped her lunch onto the ground.  This kind of empathy is wonderful.</report>
		<report>studentname thanked the janitor today for cleaning the bathroom.  It really made Mr Smith's day. Such thoughful behavior should not go unnoticed.</report>
	</positive>
</myschool>